Hello friends, today in May a video was uploaded on this channel on
how to self-respect your vehicle in the policy market. After
watching that video, one of our subscriber
commented that
in which cases it is necessary to get the vehicle inspected.
Today's video is about this.
Friends, there are three types of cases in
which we have to get the vehicle inspected and
the two cases are the last two cases,
in maximum of them it happens that
our claim gets rejected due to not getting the inspection done.
Hello friends,
my name is Harvinder Singh and welcome
to the YouTube channel of DSP Solutions.
I always try to
answer all your questions related to insurance.
If you are new to this channel or have come for the first time, then
press the subscribe button and close.
This is a part of the DSC Solutions family. Press the bell icon and
set the notifications to call
so that you do not miss any important updates.
Let's start. Friends, first of all let me make it
clear to you that when
any vehicle, bike or commercial
vehicle is inspected, it is done head-on.  There will be an
insurance, there is
no need for any insurance, if someone tells you
that there will be an insurance in the third party, they
charge us some charges for that, then you should
not attend to him, now friends, let's talk about the
number one time when you should get your vehicle
insurance, that is when your
insurance policy expires, some
reverse, it said that you have to get it insured after 90 days of expiry,
or when will you need it,
after how many days will you need it,
friends, suppose if your vehicle
insurance is expiring at 12:00 tonight
and you forget to renew your insurance
and the next day also you want to
renew your insurance in a hurry early in the morning, then also
your vehicle will be insured, it is
just like one, suppose
his old insurance company, the company whose
journey is ending, and the insurance company
goes on this year, and if it is the same, then
maybe he will do your space traveler's stand for
a day or two, but if you
change the insurance company, then it is
confirmed that at that time a new insurance
contract will be entered  At the time of signing, your vehicle will
also be modified to a very serious extent for you. To
know this, it will definitely be infected.
Friends, now comes this number two, that is,
whenever you make any important modifications to your vehicle,
any major changes, then
you have to inform the insurance company about it. The
major ones in this are getting
any CNG or
LPG kit fitted in the bike unit,
then during that time you have to get
your insurance company updated after getting it updated in the RC
and for that the insurance
company inspects your vehicle.
After inspection, they will make you pay the
premium for this coverage
and then will give you a credit policy, only then will
this coverage of yours and
this insurance mediclaim of 22 cricket. But
if you do not tell them, then if any
claim comes in the future, then the
insurance company will refuse saying that
you did
not tell the correct facts to the insurance company that the oil being
used in the vehicle has
not been updated and due to this we are
rejecting your claim, so you should also know about this.  We need to pay
special attention to this
number 3, which is the most important one. Where we tend to be
most careless is when we
buy a used car, i.e.,
we change our name on the RC
but
leave the insurance policy in the old owner's name,
thinking that when the policy
expires, a new policy will automatically be
issued in our name. However, this is not the case.
If a claim arises during this time, i.e.,
after the RC is issued in your name,
you will not receive it
because the policy is in the old owner's name
and has been issued in your name. For this,
you will also need to update your name in the insurance policy.
To know the detailed process, you
can easily view the entire process by clicking on the i button. Those who
believe that
after the policy expires, when we renew it, the
policy will be issued in our name at the same time. There is
a problem with this:
your vehicle will be inspected at some point. So,
why not get the inspection done after the RC is issued so that
you can also have the
risk cover of the vehicle for the entire time.  Now, when the RC
is made in your name, if within 14 days
you apply to change your name in the insurance policy, then there is
no need for any inspection. However, if it
exceeds the fourth day, then
you will have to get the vehicle inspected and
after this inspection, your name will be updated and included
in your insurance policy.
Friends, we have learned the three ways in which
you must get your vehicle inspected,
otherwise there may be a problem in passing your claim. I
hope
you liked the information, but there are
two ways to get the inspection done. One is by getting the
update done from the insurance company.
Nowadays, every insurance company has its own
application, this phone app has also come, through
which you can do self-destruction. So,
prefer Celebration because firstly,
you will not be charged anything. If any
torrent company
charges for this, then it will not be charged
if you change it and check it.
Second,
you can do it according to your schedule and as per your convenience. You do
not need to do any of your work yourself.  Even if you are
travelling, wait for 10 minutes,
your vehicle can get infected. I hope
you liked this information.
Like and share the video and do
not forget to subscribe to the channel. See you
in the next video with more important updates. Till then
take care of yourself and be yourself.
Thank you
Jhal.